# Jagdeep Bhoria

**Email**: jagdeep.bhoria@gmail.com **Phone number**: +33 755911578

**Preferred Role**: Test Analyst, Test Engineer, Tester, QA Engineer, Automation Tester. **Preferred Location**: Flexible, Anywhere within the UK, Europe, Asia, Middle East.

**Total Experience:** 11 years

Current Employer: Infosys Limited, India

## **Professional Profile**

A Quality Analyst with a wealth of experience delivering in-depth testing services covering financial, non-financial as well as web- based applications. As a Test Analyst and meticulous record keeper, working hand in hand with technical, non-technical colleagues and stakeholders to deliver a fit for purpose product has always been part and parcel of a long-lasting testing career.

### **Core skills**

- Exhibit a track record of participating in the full end to end of STLC (System Testing Life Cycle) on multiple transformation programmes (Test Discovery, Test Planning, Test Specification, Test Execution and Defect Management, Test Completion).
- Possess an understanding of various Test management and automation tools: HP Quality Centre (QC), Application Life Cycle Management (ALM), Jira, Microsoft Test Manager, Selenium Web driver, Tosca, Q-Test.
- Able to work on multiple projects simultaneously.
- Possess strong time management, organisational skills and very enthusiastic about software testing and the desire to deliver a fit for purpose product to the customer.
- Proficient in analysing business/ system requirement documents, writing and executing test cases, reporting and tracking defects as well as modifications.
- Broad experience gained within various software development environments (Waterfall, V-Model & Agile-Scrum).

#### **Technology**

- Test Tools: HP ALM, JIRA, Microsoft Test Manager, SOAPUI, Tosca, Selenium IDE, SOAPUI, Postman.
- Operating Systems: Microsoft Server (2008 onwards) and Workstation product suite (Win7 onwards), iOS (from v4 onwards), Android OS (from 2.0 onwards)
- Databases: Microsoft SQL server from 2008.
- Browsers: Microsoft Internet Explorer, Microsoft Edge, Apple Safari, Mozilla Firefox for Windows, Google Chrome.
- Development: Java, C#, Python, Ruby, JSON, HTML5, Gherkin
- Development Platform: Jenkins, Visual Studio, Ruby Mine, Eclipse, Notepad++
- Development Methodologies: Waterfall, V-Model, DevOps, Agile Scrum, Agile XP, Agile Kanban, BDD (SpecFlow), TDD.

#### **Career History**

#### **Automation Test Lead**

### **Compass Group France, March 2019-Present**

British multinational contract foodservice company headquartered in Chertsey, Surrey. It is the largest contract foodservice company in the world. Compass Group has operations in about 50 countries, employs over 550,000 people and serves around 5.5 billion meals a year. Compass Group is listed on the London Stock Exchange and is a constituent of the FTSE 100 Index.

Working with a team of 12 Business Analysts to carryout AT (Assembly Test), SIT and UAT on the company's legacy system (Oracle) and newly acquired SAP S/4Hana.

## Tasks/Responsibilities:

- Aid a team of 12 Business Analysts with their tests
- Handle and discuss effort estimations w.r.t each requirement, delicate the same within the team and made sure timely delivery of the deliverables
- Responsible for Manual testing across:
  Assembly, Regression, UAT and Functional testing.
- Executing tests cases on Qtest and raising defects on Jira.
- Writing and executing own test scripts and scenarios against test requirements.
- Responsible for analysing test requirements.
- Tracking and updating defects using Q test and Jira.
- Attend daily meetings with the Business Analysts.
- Automate manual test cases using Selenium Webdriver and Tosca.

### **DevOps Lead**

## AT&T, Feb 2016 -February 2019

The client has a huge infrastructure of Java based applications and Sales force applications. It needs to support and streamline its different existing processes like development, testing and deployment. Solutions to various pain areas like inconsistent automation flow, automation of regression pack for early test execution, inconsistent test execution management, no dashboard reporting mechanism, time consuming environment provisioning, troublesome release management needs to be implemented.

## Tasks/Responsibilities:

- Develop a pipeline, implementing Kafka-Zookeeper and File-beat as part of the log analytic requirement
- Track project activity milestone checks and schedule management in a smooth and efficient manner
- Interact with customer and participate in business and system requirements sessions
- Provide IT support to critical business operations and solve any reported issues with SLA
- To Dockerize their different developed applications using Docker and deploy the same on the Kubernetes Dashboard through Kubernetes
- Involved in API testing using Postman
- Created end-to-end CI/CD pipeline using GIT for SCM, MAVEN for Code build, Jenkins for continuous integration and JIRA for traceability
- Participated in KT sessions, help prepare system appreciation documents and support the Transition process
- Responsible for demos for all the deliverables, to client

## Automation Test lead METRO Dec 2014 - Jan 2016

Project involved development and implementation of different CRs and automation of the regression suite for the client's web based CRM application. Apart from the regression suite automation, it required automation of the web services using SOAP UI and load testing using Load runner.

### Tasks/Responsibilities:

- Participated in activities related to requirements elicitation, doubt clarification sessions, effort estimations
- Involved with development team to closely monitor the developed CRs and later automate the same for unit testing using Selenium Webdriver
- Single handily, mentored and managed a team of 6 members
- Developed Java based automation framework using Selenium Webdriver
- Automate, review and execution of regression test sets, using Selenium Webdriver
- Integrated the automation framework with HPQC for automatic status update of the executed automated scripts
- Bug reporting in JIRA and followed bug life cycle

### **Test Analyst**

## TESCO, October 2011 - November 2014

The client is a British multinational grocery and general merchandise retailer.

I was engaged with their customer support team to enhance their existing back end web based application which was needed for business purpose and later to automate the same.

### Tasks/Responsibilities:

- Reviewed business requirements, Epics, User stories, Acceptance criteria to facilitate the creation of test cases.
- Contributing to the development/improvement of test process and ensuring that the existing process is followed as defined in the company testing strategy document.
- Working with the project teams to define the test processes so as to ensure quality of the end product.
- Worked in close collaboration with Scrum team to define and agree Testing "definition of done".
- Actively participated in the various scrum meetings, reported progress \ impediments and ensured testing blockers were escalated to the Scrum master for resolution.
- Singled out and selected test cases to be included in the regression pack (both manual and Automation tests).
- Verified and managed result data after test execution using SQL and SQL Server Management studio database too.
- Took part in Sprint Retrospectives where lessons learnt and process improvements were recommended for adoption in future projects.
- Supported the test automation team by using Ruby, Capybara and Cucumber to create features, write scenarios and implement step definitions within Ruby Mine
- Assisted the test automation team in automation UI
- Retested all resolved defects and closed where retest was successful.

#### **Test Analyst**

## TomTom (Amsterdam, Netherlands) Oct 2008 - Sep 2011

The client is a leading manufacturer of traffic, navigation and mapping products based out of Amsterdam, Netherlands.

I was engaged with the Client's software Engineering group and working as their extended test team. Some of the work involved testing of the Backward compatibility release. With this releases, the new features released on the latest GPS devices are made available on the devices already existing in the market.

#### Tasks/Responsibility:

- Followed AGILE methodology in order to successfully execute the project
- Created manual test sets in excel sheets, get them reviewed and incorporated review comments if any
- Executed the manual test sets as part of the regression, functional/non-functional testing of the client's GPS based devices
- Created the user documentation for the assigned sub-modules
- Involved in the support and maintenance of customer environment

- Reported bugs w.r.t. the testing failures in JIRA, get them fixed and retested. This also involved keeping a track and testing of past raised bugs
- Carried out static tests on all the relevant project artifacts (Requirements, Design and Testing documentation) produced by the various workstreams to establish clarity, completeness, traceability and testability.
- Produced relevant Test Plans for parts of the system that fell within my remit.
- As part of my Test planning tasks, I worked with team to agree and embed Test entry and exit criteria for each relevant test phase.
- Defined and pursued Test data requirements (where live date was required, I worked with Database team to ensure that data was scrambled and secure).
- Created Test execution schedules to mirror agreed project release plan
- Verified all requested parts of the system and agreed functionality had been tested, to ensure that we delivered a product that is fit for purpose,
- Helped the test automation team by selecting the test cases to be automated.
- Also worked with the automation team to maintain existing framework.
- Checked and made sure that all test scripts have been executed and that all agreed quota of defects have been fixed, tested and closed.
- Produced Test completion, reports and ensured that all Test Entry and Exist criteria were met facilitating hitch-free customer sign-off.

## Education/Certification and Training.

- Bachelor of Engineering in Electronics and Telecommunication from Maharishi Dyanand University, Rohtak
- Web Service testing using SOAP UI
- Java Programming
- AGILE Scrum Methodology
- Defect Management Lifecycle: Tools & Processes (Testing Academy).

#### **Hobbies:**

- Listening to music, Playing cricket
- Love travelling